Guide to the Wheeler-Fleming Family Papers, 1862-1961
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Wheeler-Fleming Family papers 1862-1961 (bulk 1899-1918)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Wheeler family.
2.0 Linear Feet 900 Items
Two related families living in La Monte (Pettis County), Missouri.
Collection includes correspondence, photographs, financial and legal papers, poetry, cards, clippings, and genealogical information pertaining to the related Wheeler and Fleming families from La Monte, Mo. Photographs (circa 150) are mainly from the late 19th century; most are family portraits, but also include town businesses and rural scenes. Correspondence concerns crops and weather, church life, illnesses, family life, and primary school life in Bates County, Mo. (1899-1900). Includes a group of 100 letters (1908-1933) from R.A.S. Wade, a Missouri Methodist minister in California, who refers to Los Angeles area politics; church history; the Methodist Episcopal Church, South; the Masonic Home of California in De Coto, Ca.; prohibition and the temperance movement; World War I; the 1929 Depression; and the legal affairs of the Rev. J. P. Shuler. Some 100 pieces of poetry were also written by Wade and sent to the Wheelers. Genealogical materials refer to the Wheeler, Fleming, Kemp, Routsong, and McArtor or McArthur families. Collection also includes: a history of Methodist Church in La Monte, Mo.; calling cards and greeting cards; memorial booklets; land plats and deeds; records of the La Monte Woman's Missionary Society; school reports; insurance policies; and tax receipts.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Wheeler-Fleming Family Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1986-1993.
Biographical Note
Two related families living in La Monte (Pettis County), Missouri.
Collection Overview
Collection includes correspondence, photographs, financial and legal papers, poetry, cards, clippings, and genealogical information pertaining to the related Wheeler and Fleming families from La Monte, Mo. Photographs (circa 150) are mainly from the late 19th century; most are family portraits, but also include town businesses and rural scenes. Correspondence concerns crops and weather, church life, illnesses, family life, and primary school life in Bates County, Mo. (1899-1900). Includes a group of 100 letters (1908-1933) from R.A.S. Wade, a Missouri Methodist minister in California, who refers to Los Angeles area politics; church history; the Methodist Episcopal Church, South; the Masonic Home of California in De Coto, Ca.; prohibition and the temperance movement; World War I; the 1929 Depression; and the legal affairs of the Rev. J. P. Shuler. Some 100 pieces of poetry were also written by Wade and sent to the Wheelers. Genealogical materials refer to the Wheeler, Fleming, Kemp, Routsong, and McArtor or McArthur families. Collection also includes: a history of Methodist Church in La Monte, Mo.; calling cards and greeting cards; memorial booklets; land plats and deeds; records of the La Monte Woman's Missionary Society; school reports; insurance policies; and tax receipts.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Wheeler family
Fleming family
Kemp family
Routsong family
McArtor family
Wade, R. A. S.
Shuler, J. P., Reverend
La Monte Methodist Church -- La Monte (Mo.) -- History
Methodist Episcopal Church, South -- California
Masonic Home of California (De Coto, Calif.)
La Monte Woman's Missionary Society
Missouri -- Social life and customs
La Monte (Mo.) -- Economic conditions
Missouri -- History
World War, 1914-1918
Prohibition -- United States
Agriculture -- Missouri
Education -- Missouri -- Bates County
Genealogy
Depressions -- 1929 -- United States
Temperance -- United States
Photographs
California -- Politics and government
Contents of Collection
- Correspondence Series, 1877-1934
  - Correspondence, 1877-1934 and undated, (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - R. H. Wade Correspondence, 1908-1933, (2 folders)
- Writings and Speeches Series, 1866-1938
  - R.H. Wade Poetry (Box 1)
  - History of LaMonte, Mo., Methodist Church, 1866-1958
- Financial Papers Series, 1865-1915
  - Tax Receipts, 1865-1915 (Box 1)
- Photographs Series, 1880-1960
  - Photographs, circa 1880-1960 (Box 2)
  - Photographs, circa 1880-1930 (Box 3)
- Printed Materials Series, 1860-1949
  - Printed Materials, circa 1860-1949, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - In Memoriam Books, 1890-1934
  - "The Epitome" School Yearbook, 1921
- Legal Papers Series, 1863-1940
  - Legal Papers, 1863-1940, (3 folders) (Box 4)
  - Land Deeds, 1910-1931
- Other Materials Series, 1883-1906 and undated
  - Genealogical Papers (Box 4)
  - Clippings
  - Women's Societies Records, 1883-1906
- Oversize Materials Series, 1932 and undated
  - State Teacher's College of Central Missouri at Warrenburg Diploma, 1932 (Box 5)
  - Photographs